# **Zhengkai Jiang**

Address Gumei Road 1528

Xuhui District, Shanghai

kaikaijiang.jzk@gmail.com

Website Github jiangzhengkai.github.io github.com/jiangzhengkai

## **Personal Profile**

**Email** 

Self-motivated deep learning algorithm researcher at Tencent Youtu Lab. I have publish several papers on top conferences such as NeurIPS, CVPR, ECCV and AAAI. My research interests mainly lie in object detection, video understanding and generative model.

# **Research Interest**

• Object Detection, Instance Segmentation, Video Understanding, Image-to-Image Translation

### Education

#### 2017-2020 University of Chinese Academy of Sciences

National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition,

Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China

Master in Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System, Supervisor: Prof.Shiming Xiang

Overall GPA: 3.7/4.0, Ranking: **Top 5%** Fields: Computer Vision and Deep Learning

#### 2013-2017 Bachelor of Automation

Northeastern University, Shenyang, China Overall GPA: 91.3/100, Ranking: 1/37(2/248)

# **Experience**

Jul. 2020 - Now Tencent Youtu Lab

Full-Time Researcher, Shanghai, China Topic: Image and Video Understanding

Apr. 2019 - Apr. 2020 Megvii Research

Research Intern, Beijing, China

Topic: General Object Detection, Mentored by Dr. Gang Yu and Zeming Li

Jan. 2018 - Mar. 2019 Horizon Robotics

Research Intern, Beijing, China

Topic: Video Object Detection, Mentored by Dr. Qian Zhang

Mar. 2017 - Sep. 2017 Sensetime Research

Research Intern, Beijing, China

Topic: Pedestrian Attribute Classification, Mentored by Dr. Jing Shao

# **Selected Projects**

Jul. 2020 - Dec. 2020 Gaze Redirection

We propose a novel flow-based Ugaze network to redirect the gaze to the camera not the screen to improve the eye contact. World's first eye contact is online at Tencent Meeting

## **Publication**

#### Conference

AutoAssign: Differentiable Label Assignment for Dense Object Detection
 Benjin Zhu, Jianfeng Wang, Zhengkai Jiang, Fuhang Zong, Songtao Liu, Zeming Li, Jian Sun
 In Submission

**■** Fine-Grained Dynamic Routing for Object Detection

Lin Song, Yanwei Li, **Zhengkai Jiang**, Zeming Li, Hongbin Sun, Jian Sun, Nanning Zheng Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

• Rethinking Learnable Tree Filter for Generic Feature Transform

Lin Song, Yanwei Li, **Zhengkai Jiang**, Zeming Li, Xiangyu Zhang, Hongbin Sun, Jian Sun, Nanning Zheng

Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

Learning Where to Focus for Efficient Video Object Detection

**Zhengkai Jiang**, Yu Liu, Ceyuan Yang, Jihao Liu, Peng Gao, Qian Zhang, Shiming Xiang, Chunhong Pan

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020

Class-balanced Grouping and Sampling for Point Cloud 3D Object Detection

Benjin Zhu, **Zhengkai Jiang**, Xiangxin Zhou, Zeming Li, Gang Yu NuScenes Winner in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) WAD Workshop, 2019

Dynamic Fusion with Intra- and Inter- Modality Attention Flow for Visual Question Answering
Peng Gao, Zhengkai Jiang, Haoxuan You, Pan Lu, Steven Hoi, Xiaogang Wang, Hongsheng Li
IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019, Oral

Video Object Detection with Locally-Weighted Deformable Neighbours

**Zhengkai Jiang**, Peng Gao, Chaoxu Guo, Qian Zhang, Shiming Xiang, Chunhong Pan Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2019

# **Academic Competitions**

- 1st at the Objects 365 Challenge, 2020
- 1st at the NuScenes 3D Detection of CVPR WAD workshop, 2019
- 3rd at the Instance Segmentation of ECCV COCO Workshop, 2018

#### **Honors and Awards**

- Outstanding Student in Institution of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences, 2020
- Outstanding Student in Institution of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences, 2019
- Excellent Graduate in Liaoning Province, 2017
- 1st class Scholarship of Northeastern University, 2014, 2016
- 2nd Prize on National Mathematical Contest in Modeling(in China), 2015
- 3st Prize on Final Chinese Mathematics Competitions(in Fuzhou, China), 2016
- 1st Prize on Chinese Mathematics Competitions(in Shenyang, China), 2015

- 2st Prize on Final Chinese Mathematics Competitions(in Wuhan, China), 2015
- 1st Prize on Chinese Mathematics Competitions(in Shenyang, China), 2015
- National Scholarship (Top 0.2% students in China), 2016
- National Scholarship (Top 0.2% students in China), 2015
- National Scholarship (Top 0.2% students in China), 2014

# **Professorial Services**

#### **Conference Reviewer**

- Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence, 2021
- International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2021

#### **Journal Reviewer**

■ International Journal of Computer Vision

## **Skills**

Programming Languages Deep Learning Frameworks Backend Framework Languages Python, C++ PyTorch, Mxnet, Caffe CUDA, MPI Chinese, English